export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following positions falls under lower-level management?",
A: "Accounts clerk",
B: "Chief executive officer",
C: "Human resource officer",
D: "Machine operator",
answer: "D. Machine operator",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Tom, Dick and Harry from different departments, are assigned to a new project. The structure under which they report to the project manager is",
A: "functional structure.",
B: "geographical structure.",
C: "matrix structure.",
D: "product structure.",
answer: "C. matrix structure.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The conversion of gold into a ring is referred to as",
A: "commerce.",
B: "construction.",
C: "extraction.",
D: "manufacturing.",
answer: "D. manufacturing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following occupations falls under tertiary production?",
A: "Carpentry",
B: "Farming",
C: "Mining",
D: "Teaching",
answer: "D. Teaching",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A partnership in which all partners have unlimited liability is",
A: "dormant partnership.",
B: "limited partnership.",
C: "nominal partnership.",
D: "ordinary partnership.",
answer: "D. ordinary partnership.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A retired partner whose name is still used in the business is",
A: "Limited partner",
B: "Nominal partner",
C: "Ordinary partner",
D: "Sleeping partner",
answer: "B. Nominal partner",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Job instructions take the form of",
A: "diagonal communication.",
B: "downward communication.",
C: "lateral communication.",
D: "upward communication.",
answer: "B. downward communication.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. One of the barriers to effective communication is",
A: "attentiveness.",
B: "clarity of expression.",
C: "feedback.",
D: "illegible handwriting.",
answer: "D. illegible handwriting.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Developing alternatives is a method used in the",
A: "co-ordinating function.",
B: "directing function.",
C: "organizing function.",
D: "planning function.",
answer: "D. planning function.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. An offer is sale of goods can be terminated due to",
A: "lapse of time.",
B: "prompt delivery of service.",
C: "quality of the goods.",
D: "relationship of the parties.",
answer: "A. lapse of time",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following business organizations is a legal person?",
A: "Company",
B: "Co-operative Society",
C: "Partnership",
D: "Sole proprietorship",
answer: "D. Sole proprietorship.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. One example of the external stakeholders of a company is its",
A: "customers.",
B: "employees.",
C: "shareholders.",
D: "management.",
answer: "A. customers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The responsibility of businesses towards government include",
A: "offering of scholarships to needy students",
B: "payment of taxes.",
C: "the payment of salaries to its employees.",
D: "the provision of goods and services.",
answer: "B. payment of taxes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The subject matter of collective bargaining which deals directly with disputes is",
A: "grievance handling",
B: "hours of work.",
C: "job security.",
D: "welfare service.",
answer: "A. grievance handling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A compulsory payment by employees on their income is",
A: "capital gains tax.",
B: "corporate tax.",
C: "Pay-As-You-Earn.",
D: "specific tax.",
answer: "C. Pay-As-You-Earn.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. One effect to inflation is an increase in",
A: "employment.",
B: "prices of goods and services.",
C: "production level.",
D: "purchasing power.",
answer: "B. prices of goods and services",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Until an insurance contract is signed, the applicant for the policy is",
A: "assured.",
B: "beneficiary.",
C: "insured.",
D: "proposer.",
answer: "D. proposer.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The factor by which taxes are paid according to the financial position of the firm is the",
A: "ability to pay.",
B: "ability to persuade.",
C: "benefit received.",
D: "sales received.",
answer: "C. benefit received",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The individual’s portion of a company’s capital is",
A: "bond.",
B: "debenture.",
C: "shares.",
D: "venture capital.",
answer: "C. shares.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The document used by an importer to order goods from an exporter is",
A: "bill of exchange.",
B: "bill of lading.",
C: "indent.",
D: "invoice.",
answer: "C. indent.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The business entity formed by an Act of Parliament is a",
A: "co-operative society.",
B: "public Company.",
C: "public corporation.",
D: "sole proprietorship.",
answer: "C. public corporation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A valid contractual agreement is",
A: "a legally binding relationship.",
B: "when a buyer and seller meet in a market.",
C: "when goods and services are delivered.",
D: "when the parties owe each other",
answer: "A. a legally binding relationship",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The liability of a sole proprietor is unlimited. This means-that the",
A: "business is operated by only one owner.",
B: "debt owed to the owner of the business can be transferred to customers. ‘",
C: "owner of the business can offer after sales service to customers.",
D: "sole owner of the business is the risk bearer.",
answer: "D. sole owner of the business is the risk bearer",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. One of the features of regressive tax ‘system is that, tax rate",
A: "declines as tax base increase.",
B: "increases as the tax base increases.",
C: "is always constant.",
D: "is always proportionate to tax base.",
answer: "B. increases as the tax base increases.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Communication is said to be effective when the",
A: "feedback is delayed.",
B: "intended meaning and the perceived meaning are the same.",
C: "intended meaning is different from the perceived meaning.",
D: "objectives are vague.",
answer: "B. intended meaning and the perceived meaning are the same",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The business resource which serves as a unit of account is",
A: "labour",
B: "machine",
C: "material",
D: "money.",
answer: "D. money",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Attracting a pool of qualified applicants is",
A: "induction.",
B: "promotion.",
C: "recruitment.",
D: "selection.",
answer: "C. recruitment.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following Maslow’s hierarchy of needs deals with status symbols?",
A: "Physiological needs",
B: "Safety needs",
C: "Affection needs",
D: "Esteem needs",
answer: "D. Esteem needs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The practice of moving workers from one schedule to another is",
A: "job description.",
B: "job evaluation.",
C: "job rotation.",
D: "job specification.",
answer: "C. job rotation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Unemployment occurs when people who are available and want to work",
A: "are denied jobs.",
B: "are selective jobs.",
C: "are under paid.",
D: "cannot find paid jobs.",
answer: "D. cannot find paid jobs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The organization responsible for economic integration in West Africa is",
A: "ACP.",
B: "ECOWAS.",
C: "IME",
D: "UNCTAD.",
answer: "B. ECOWAS",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. An example of input device is",
A: "chip.",
B: "monitor.",
C: "disc.",
D: "mouse.",
answer: "D. mouse",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A piece of land was bought in 2008 at the value of GH¢ 2,000 and sold at GH¢3,000 in 2013. Calculate 10% rate of tax on the gain.",
A: "GH¢ 1,000",
B: "GH¢ 300",
C: "GH¢ 200",
D: "GH¢ 100",
answer: "D. GHC100",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following sources is an external means of finance?",
A: "Bank loan",
B: "Cash",
C: "Retained earnings",
D: "Shares",
answer: "A. Bank loan",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The principle of insurance which precludes the insured from making profit is",
A: "contribution.",
B: "insurable interest.",
C: "proximate cause.",
D: "utmost bank",
answer: "A. contribution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The bankers’ bank refers to",
A: "central bank.",
B: "commercial bank",
C: "development bank.",
D: "merchant bank.",
answer: "A. central bank.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Revision of decision to meet dynamic changes is the,",
A: "first step in decision making.",
B: "second step in decision making.",
C: "third step in decision making.",
D: "last step in decision making.",
answer: "D. last step in decision making",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. An example of informal communication is",
A: "circular.",
B: "grapevine.",
C: "memorandum.",
D: "workshop",
answer: "B. grapevine.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following documents regulates the internal administration of a company?",
A: "Articles of Association",
B: "Certificate of Incorporation",
C: "Certificate of Trading",
D: "Memorandum of Association",
answer: "A. Articles of Association",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The provision of good drinking water is a corporate social responsibility of business towards",
A: "community.",
B: "consumer.",
C: "government.",
D: "suppliers.",
answer: "A. community.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The responsibility of a company towards its shareholders is the",
A: "award of contract.",
B: "payment of corporate taxes.",
C: "payment of dividend.",
D: "payment of salaries.",
answer: "C. payment of dividend",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. A tax is proportionate when",
A: "its rate increases as the tax base increases.",
B: "its rate remains the same regardless of the size of the tax base.",
C: "the rate declines as the tax base increases.",
D: "the rate is determined by the government.",
answer: "C. the rate declines as the tax base increases.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. An element of contract which is related to age is",
A: "capacity of parties.",
B: "consideration of parties.",
C: "legality of purpose.",
D: "offer and acceptable.",
answer: "A. capacity of parties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following features is common to West African economics?",
A: "Capital intensive agricultural method",
B: "Dependence on single product for export",
C: "High level of employment",
D: "High standard of living",
answer: "B. Dependence on single product for export",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Another name for visual display unit is",
A: "bar code reader.",
B: "floppy disc.",
C: "monitor.",
D: "system unit.",
answer: "C. monitor.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Market segmentation based on regions and cities is",
A: "buyer behavior",
B: "demographic.",
C: "geographic.",
D: "psychographic.",
answer: "C. geographic.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The management function which links various activities towards a common goal is",
A: "co-ordination.",
B: "decision making.",
C: "forecasting.",
D: "motivation.",
answer: "A. co-ordination.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A minor is a person who",
A: "has a voting right.",
B: "has no contractual capacity.",
C: "is insane.",
D: "ratifies a contract.",
answer: "B. has no contractual capacity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The management function which ensures that standards are maintained is",
A: "planning.",
B: "organizing.",
C: "directing.",
D: "controlling.",
answer: "D. controlling.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The set of activities used by a firm to reach its customers is",
A: "place",
B: "pricing.",
C: "product.",
D: "promotion.",
answer: "D. promotion.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]